Guide to the Records of the Office of the Chancellor and Executive Vice President: David D. Henry and Carroll V. Newsom, John E. Ivey, Jr., George D. Stoddard, and Russell D. Niles 1942-1966 (Bulk 1952-1956) RG 6.0
New York University Archives
- Series IV: Russell D. Niles
  - Subseries B: 1964 - 1965
    - Sub-Subseries C: Schools, Divisions, Institutes
      - Washington Square College of Arts and Science, 1964-1965 (Box 35, Folder 18)
      - University Senate, 1964-1965 (Box 36, Folder 1)
        bar code: 3 1142 042255102
      - Students, Dean of, 1962-1965 (Box 36, Folder 2)
      - Students - Dress Regulations, 1964-1965 (Box 36, Folder 3)
      - Students - General, 1965-1965 (Box 36, Folder 4)
      - University Commission on Graduate Work, 1963-1964 (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - University Commission on Graduate Work, 1964-1965 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Sub-Subseries D: All-University Departments
      - Biology, 1960-1964 (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - Chemistry, 1962-1965 (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Classics, 1962-1964 (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - Economics, 1963-1964 (Box 36, Folder 10)
      - English, 1961-1964 (Box 36, Folder 11)
      - Geology, 1960-1964 (Box 36, Folder 12)
      - German, 1964-1965 (Box 36, Folder 13)
      - Government and International, 1961-1965 (Box 36, Folder 14)
      - History, 1961-1964 (Box 36, Folder 15)
      - Mathematics, 1961-1964 (Box 36, Folder 16)
      - Music, 1963-1964 (Box 37, Folder 1)
        bar code: 3 1142 042255110
      - Chemistry, 1962-1965 (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - Physics, 1960-1965 (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - Psychology, 1961-1965 (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - Romance Languages and Literature, 1961-1965 (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - Slavic Languages and Literature, 1965 (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - Sociology and Anthropology, 1960-1964 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Subseries C: 1965 - 1966
    - Sub-Subseries A: Administration
      - Assistant Executive Vice-President, 1965-1966 (Box 37, Folder 8)
      - Board of Trustees - Alumni Trustees, 1965-1966 (Box 37, Folder 9)
      - Board of Trustees - Appointments, 1959-1966 (Box 37, Folder 10)
      - Board of Trustees - General, 1965-1966 (Box 37, Folder 11)
      - Budget Advisory Group, 1965-1966 (Box 37, Folder 12)
      - Budget Advisory Group, 1965-1966 (Box 37, Folder 13)
      - Budget, Director of, 1965-1967 (Box 38, Folder 1)
        bar code: 3 1142 042255128
      - Business Manager, 1964-1966 (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Officers Group, 1965-1966 (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - President, 1964-1966 (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Provost - University Heights, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - Public Relations, Director of, 1961-1966 (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - Treasurer, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - University Village - Faculty-Staff Housing, 1964-1966 (Box 38, Folder 8)
      - AVP for Business Affairs Construction, 1965-1966 (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - Vice-President for Business Affairs, 1965-1966 (Box 38, Folder 10)
      - Vice-President and Secretary, 1965-1966 (Box 38, Folder 11)
      - Vice-President for Scientific Affairs, 1964-1965 (Box 38, Folder 12)
      - Vice-President for Scientific Affairs, 1965-1966 (Box 38, Folder 13)
      - Vice-President for University Affairs, 1965-1966 (Box 39, Folder 1)
        bar code: 3 1142 042255136
    - Sub-Subseries B: Schools, Colleges, Divisions
      - Academic Administrators, 1964-1965 (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Administrative Council, 1964-1965 (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - Admissions, 1965-1966 (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - Alumni Federation, 1966 (Box 39, Folder 5)
      - American Association of University Professors, 1961-1966 (Box 39, Folder 6)
      - Arts, School of the, 1964-1971 (Box 39, Folder 7)
      - Commerce, School of, 1965-1966 (Box 39, Folder 8)
      - Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences, 1965-1966 (Box 39, Folder 9)
      - Dentistry, College of, 1965-1966 (Box 39, Folder 10)
      - Education, School of, 1962-1966 (Box 39, Folder 11)
      - Education, School of, 1962-1966 (Box 39, Folder 12)
      - Engineering and Science, School of, 1964-1966 (Box 40, Folder 1)
        bar code: 3 1142 042255144
      - Fine Arts, Institute of, 1965-1966 (Box 40, Folder 2)
      - General Education and Extension Services, Division of, 1965-1966 (Box 40, Folder 3)
      - Graduate School of Arts and Science, 1964-1966 (Box 40, Folder 4)
      - Graduate School of Business Administration, 1964-1966 (Box 40, Folder 5)
      - Graduate School of Public Administration, 1965-1966 (Box 40, Folder 6)
      - Law, School of, 1965-1966 (Box 40, Folder 7)
      - Medical Center, 1965-1966 (Box 40, Folder 8)
      - Social Work, Graduate School of, 1965-1966 (Box 40, Folder 9)
      - University College of Arts and Science, 1965-1966 (Box 40, Folder 10)
      - University Valley - Sterling Forest, 1962-1966 (Box 40, Folder 11)
      - Washington Square College of Arts and Science, 1965-1966 (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Sub-Subseries C: All-University Departments
      - Committee of Deans of Liberal Arts, 1964-1966 (Box 40, Folder 13)
      - Committee on Problems of Schools and Business, 1964-1965 (Box 40, Folder 14)
      - Computer Research in the Humanities, Institute for University Heights, 1966 (Box 41, Folder 1)
        bar code: 3 1142 042255151
      - Deans Council, 1965-1966 (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Distinguished Professors Selection Committee, 1962-1965 (Box 41, Folder 3)
      - Gifts - General, 1964-1966 (Box 41, Folder 4)
      - Institute of Economic Affairs - Challenge Magazine, 1962-1966 (Box 41, Folder 5)
      - Faculty Club, 1964-1966 (Box 41, Folder 6)
      - Financial Aid, Dean of, 1965-1966 (Box 41, Folder 7)
      - General Correspondence, 1964-1966 (Box 41, Folder 8)
      - Grading System, 1962-1964 (Box 41, Folder 9)
      - Graduate Work, University Commission on, 1965-1966 (Box 41, Folder 10)
      - Hebrew Studies, Institute of, 1964-1966 (Box 41, Folder 11)
      - Housing, 1965-1966 (Box 41, Folder 12)
      - International Student Center, 1960-1966 (Box 42, Folder 1)
        bar code: 3 1142 042255169
      - International Studies, Center for, 1964-1966 (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - International Studies, Center for, 1964-1966 (Box 42, Folder 3)
      - Krzyzanowski, Ludwik (Graduate School of Arts and Sciences), 1965-1966 (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - Libraries, Director of, 1965-1966 (Box 42, Folder 5)
      - Special Project - Henry Kaufman Center for Camp Leadership, 1960-1963 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Sub-Subseries D: Space and Buildings
      - Alterations - Budget Adjustment, 1957-1965 (Box 42, Folder 7)
      - Alterations - Budget Adjustment, 1957-1965 (Box 42, Folder 8)
      - Alterations - Budget Adjustment, 1957-1965 (Box 42, Folder 9)
      - Alterations Lists, 1963-1965 (Box 43, Folder 1)
        bar code: 3 1142 042255177
      - Athletic Facility, Washington Square Center, 1963-1966 (Box 43, Folder 2)
      - Architect - University, 1964-1966 (Box 43, Folder 3)
      - Biology, 1963-1964 (Box 43, Folder 4)
      - 707 Broadway, 1965-1966 (Box 43, Folder 5)
      - Brown Building, 1964 (Box 43, Folder 6)
      - Butler Hall - University Heights, 1964 (Box 43, Folder 7)
      - Chemical Building - University Heights, 1964 (Box 43, Folder 8)
      - Chemical Department, 1964 (Box 43, Folder 9)
      - Commerce Building, 1964-1966 (Box 43, Folder 10)
      - Computer Laboratory, 1964 (Box 44, Folder 1)
        bar code: 3 1142 042255185
      - Construction Alterations and Acquisitions, 1951-1966 (Box 44, Folder 2)
      - Continuing Education, School of, 1965-1966 (Box 44, Folder 3)
      - Dental Center, 1964-1965 (Box 44, Folder 4)
      - Dormitory - Heights, 1965-1966 (Box 44, Folder 5)
      - Education Center, 1965-1966 (Box 44, Folder 6)
      - Education Center, 1965-1966 (Box 44, Folder 7)
      - Education Center, 1965-1966 (Box 44, Folder 8)
      - Education, School of, 1964 (Box 44, Folder 9)
      - Faculty Club, 1964 (Box 44, Folder 10)
      - 55 Fifth Avenue, 1964 (Box 44, Folder 11)
      - Graduate School, Business Administration, 1965-1966 (Box 44, Folder 12)
      - Gould Hall, 1964 (Box 44, Folder 13)
      - Gould Student Center, 1964 (Box 44, Folder 14)
      - Health Services, 1964 (Box 44, Folder 15)
      - Johnson, Philip (Washington Square Center), 1959-1965 (Box 44, Folder 16)
      - Library, 1964 (Box 44, Folder 17)
      - Library, Elmer Bobst, 1963-1966 (Box 44, Folder 18)
      - Library, Elmer Bobst, 1963-1966 (Box 44, Folder 19)
      - Library, Elmer Bobst, 1963-1966 (Box 45, Folder 1)
        bar code: 3 1142 042255193
      - Library, Programming Committee, 1963-1966 (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Library (Site Problems), 1958-1966 (Box 45, Folder 3)
      - Library (Site Problems), 1958-1966 (Box 45, Folder 4)
      - Library (Site Problems), 1958-1966 (Box 45, Folder 5)
      - New Library (Invoices), 1965 (Box 45, Folder 6)
      - Main Building Block, 1963-1966 (Box 45, Folder 7)
      - Minutes, 1964 (Box 45, Folder 8)
      - Monthly Report to the Chancellor, 1963-1964 (Box 45, Folder 9)
      - Philosophy, 1964 (Box 45, Folder 10)
      - Physics - Andre Meyer Hall, 1962-1966 (Box 45, Folder 11)
      - Press Annex, 1964 (Box 46, Folder 1)
        bar code: 3 1142 042255201
      - Rubin International Residence Hall, 1964 (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Science Buildings, 1964-1965 (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - South Hall, 1964 (Box 46, Folder 4)
      - Space (Beck), 1962-1965 (Box 46, Folder 5)
      - Space (Beck), 1962-1965 (Box 46, Folder 6)
      - Space (Beck), 1962-1965 (Box 46, Folder 7)
      - Space Requests (Budget), 1963-1964 (Box 46, Folder 8)
      - Space Studies, 1965-1966 (Box 46, Folder 9)
      - Space Studies, 1965-1966 (Box 47, Folder 1)
        bar code: 3 1142 042255219
      - Summary of New Construction - Alterations, Acquisitions, and Related Financing, 1964 (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Technology II (Heights), 1963-1966 (Box 47, Folder 3)
        - Letter from Martin L. Beck to Hamilton P. Smith, 1964 (Box 47)
        - Letter from Martin L. Beck to Marcel Breuer, 1965 (Box 47)
        - Letter from Marel Breuer to Chancellor Niles, 1965 (Box 47)
        - Letter from Werner A. Baum to Marcel Breuer, 1965 (Box 47)
        - Letter from Marcel Breuer to Werner A. Baum, 1965 (Box 47)
      - Technology II (Heights), 1963-1966 (Box 47, Folder 4)
        - Letter from Hamilton P. Smith to Martin L. Beck, 1965 (Box 47)
        - Letter from Chancellor Russell D. Niles to Hamilton P. Smith, 1965 (Box 47)
        - Letter from Hamilton P. Smith to Chancellor Russell D. Niles, 1965 (Box 47)
        - Letter from Hamilton P. Smith to Martin L. Beck, 1966 (Box 47)
        - Letter from Hamilton P. Smith to Martin L. Beck, 1966 (Box 47)
        - Letter from Russell D. Niles to Hamilton P. Smith, 1966 (Box 47)
        - Letter from Hamilton P. Smith to Russell D. Niles, 1966 (Box 47)
        - Photostat of Letter from Hamilton P. Smith to Martin L. Beck, 1966 (Box 47)
        - Letter from John M. O'Mara to Hamilton Smith (Box 47)
        - Letter from Hamilton P. Smith to John O'Mara, 1966 (Box 47)
        - Letter from Hamilton P. Smith to Russell D. Niles, 1966 (Box 47)
        - Letter from Hamilton P. Smith to Russell D. Niles, 1966 (Box 47)
        - Letter from Russell D. Niles to Hamilton P. Smith, 1966 (Box 47)
        - Photostat of Letter from Hamilton P. Smith to Martin L. Beck, 1965 (Box 47)
      - University Heights - General, 1963-1966 (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - 19 University Place, 1964-1966 (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - 19 University Place, 1964-1966 (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - 25 Waverly Place, 1964-1966 (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - Washington Square - General, 1963-1966 (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Washington Square - General, 1963-1966 (Box 47, Folder 10)
      - Washington Square - Properties, 1965-1966 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Subseries D: Subject Files (1964 - 1966)
    - Sub-Subseries A: Administrative Topical Subjects
      - Chemistry Department - New Department Head, 1964-1965 (Box 48, Folder 1)
        bar code: 3 1142 042255227
      - Hamermesh, Morton, 1964-1965 (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - Nursing, School of, 1964-1966 (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Nursing, School of, 1957-1966 (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Poverty, War on, 1964-1965 (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - Questionnaires, 1963-1966 (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - Reports, Annual Progress, 1962-1965 (Box 48, Folder 7)
      - Schweitzer, Albert, Chair in the Humanities, 1964-1966 (Box 48, Folder 8)
      - Science Development, 1964-1966 (Box 48, Folder 9)
      - Senate - Elected Members, 1964-1966 (Box 48, Folder 10)
      - Stoddard, George D., 1964-1966 (Box 48, Folder 11)
      - Student Affairs, Assistant to the President for, 1965-1966 (Box 48, Folder 12)
      - Students, Dean of, 1963-1965 (Box 48, Folder 13)
      - United States Government - HEW, 1964-1966 (Box 48, Folder 14)
      - United States Government - Higher Education Act, 1965 (Box 49, Folder 1)
        bar code: 3 1142 042255235
      - University Heights Council, 1964-1966 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Sub-Subseries B: Senate and Deans Council Minutes
      - Senate Minutes and Memoranda, 1965-1966 (Box 49, Folder 3)
      - Senate Minutes and Memoranda, 1963-1964 (Box 49, Folder 4)
      - Senate Minutes and Memoranda, 1960-1963 (Box 49, Folder 5)
      - Senate Minutes and Reports, 1961-1962 (Box 49, Folder 6)
      - Senate Minutes and Reports, 1960-1961 (Box 49, Folder 7)
      - Senate Minutes and Reports, 1959-1960 (Box 49, Folder 8)
      - Senate Memoranda, 1959-1964 (Box 49, Folder 9)
      - Deans Council Minutes, 1961-1962 (Box 49, Folder 10)
      - Deans Council Minutes, 1960-1961 (Box 49, Folder 11)
      - Deans Council Minutes, 1959-1960 (Box 49, Folder 12)
      - Deans Council Minutes and Memoranda, 1958-1959 (Box 49, Folder 13)
      - Deans Council Minutes and Reports, 1957-1958 (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - Sub-Subseries C: Mission Statements
      - Ford Foundation, 1962-1963 (Box 50, Folder 1)
        bar code: 3 1142 042255243
      - Ford Foundation, 1963 (Box 50, Folder 2)
      - Arts and Sciences, 1961-1963 (Box 50, Folder 3)
      - Proposed School of Creative Arts and Communications, 1962-1963 (Box 50, Folder 4)
      - Division of General Education, 1958-1962 (Box 50, Folder 5)
      - School of Medicine, 1960-1963 (Box 50, Folder 6)
      - College of Dentistry, 1962-1963 (Box 50, Folder 7)
      - School of Law, 1962-1963 (Box 50, Folder 8)
      - Graduate School of Arts and Science, 1962-1963 (Box 50, Folder 9)
      - Graduate School of Social Work, 1962-1963 (Box 51, Folder 1)
        bar code: 3 1142 042255250
      - School of Retailing, 1962-1963 (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - Graduate School of Public Administration, 1962-1963 (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - School of Engineering, 1960-1962 (Box 51, Folder 4)
      - School of Engineering, 1962-1963 (Box 51, Folder 5)
      - School of Education, 1957-1963 (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - Graduate School of Business Administration, 1962-1963 (Box 51, Folder 7)
      - School of Commerce, 1962-1963 (Box 51, Folder 8)
      - University College, 1962-1963 (Box 52, Folder 1)
        bar code: 3 1142 042255268
      - Washington Square College, 1962 (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Washington Square College, 1962 (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - Oversize, undated (Box 52, Folder 4)
- Series V: Additional Accession
  - College for Independent Study, 1958-1959 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    bar code: 3 1142 042255458
  - College for Independent Study, 1959-1960 (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Hofstra College, 1960-1961 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Housing and Food Services, 1961 (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - Institutional Research, Office of, 1958-1959 (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - Israel-International Cooperation Administration Project, 1960-1961 (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - Laboratory of Learning, 1953-1955 (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - Library (Washington Square), 1959-1960 (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - Loeb Student Center (Washington Square), 1955-1958 (Box 71, Folder 9)
  - Long Island University, 1952-1953 (Box 71, Folder 10)
  - Mathematics and Mechanics, Institute for, 1951-1952 (Box 71, Folder 11)
  - Mathematical Sciences, Institute of, 1952-1958 (Box 71, Folder 12)
  - Mathematical Sciences, Institute of, 1959-1960 (Box 71, Folder 13)
  - Mathematical Sciences, Institute of, 1959-1960 (Box 71, Folder 14)
  - Records - Referred, 1960-1963 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    bar code: 3 1142 042255466
  - Records - Referred, 1963-1964 (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - Religious Activities - Interfaith Council, 1954-1960 (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - Religious Activities - Protestant Group-University Christian Foundation, 1959-1961 (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - Registrar, 1961-1962 (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - Self-Study - Interim Report, 1955 (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - Self-Study - Interim Report, 1955-1956 (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Television Production Center, 1959-1961 (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - Town Hall - Preliminary Survey, 1956-1957 (Box 72, Folder 9)
  - Vice-President - Secretary, 1956-1958 (Box 72, Folder 10)
  - Vice-President - Secretary, 1961 (Box 72, Folder 11)
  - Washington Square 5, 1950-1952 (Box 72, Folder 12)
  - Wugen, William, 1946-1954 (Box 72, Folder 13)